Mertz mss., 1902-2019 LMC 2914
Lilly Library
- Personal
  - "80 Clues to the Mystery of Life" - 80th birthday gift from Carol Whitney and Jean McMellen, 2009 (Box 128, Folder 35)
  - "Tabula" - Oak Park and River Forest High School literary magazines, 1943-1945 (Box 128, Folder 36)
    Includes works by Mertz
  - "Tabula" - Oak Park and River Forest High School yearbook, 1945 (Box 129, Folder 1)
  - American University in Cairo - Dr. Barbara Mertz fountain, 2009? (Box 129, Folder 2)
  - Address books, undated (Box 129, Folder 3)
  - Alex Cooper auction of Mertz's jewelry collection, 2015 (Box 129, Folder 4)
  - Jewelry collection inventory, 1993 (Box 129, Folder 5)
  - Jewelry research material, undated (Box 129, Folder 6)
  - Jewelry certifications and appraisals, 1990-1994 (Box 129, Folder 7)
  - Jewelry price and inventory binders, undated; 2 Folders (Box 129, Folder 8-9)
  - "Diatribes", 1987-1994; 2 Folders (Box 129, Folder 10-11)
  - Memorial book and funeral guest book, 2013 (Box 129, Folder 12)
  - Lists and notes (folders 1-4), 1993-2012; 4 Folders (Box 129, Folder 13-16)
  - Lists and notes (folder 5), 1993-2012 (Box 130, Folder 1)
  - Lists and notes (folders 6-16), 1993-2012; 11 Folders (Box 135, Folder 3-13)
  - Postcard collection, undated; 12 Folders (Box 130, Folder 2-13)
  - Travel diaries, notes and ephemera
    - Florence, 1997 (Box 130, Folder 14)
    - "Near Eastern Tour", 1966 (Box 130, Folder 15)
    - Cambridge, 1995 (Box 130, Folder 16)
    - European tour, 1960? (Box 130, Folder 17)
    - "Richard III trip with Marge Laurence", 1965? (Box 130, Folder 18)
    - England, 1971-1976? (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Greece/Egypt/England, 1961 (Box 131, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1971-1972? (Box 131, Folder 3)
    - Egypt, 1989 (Box 131, Folder 4)
    - Egypt, 1991; 3 Folders (Box 131, Folder 5-7)
    - Egypt, 1993-1994; 3 Folders (Box 131, Folder 8-10)
    - Egypt, 1995-1996; 3 Folders (Box 131, Folder 11-13)
    - Egypt, 1997; 2 Folders (Box 131, Folder 14-15)
    - Egypt, 1999 (Box 131, Folder 16)
    - Egypt, 2000-2001 (Box 131, Folder 17)
    - Egypt, 2002 (Box 131, Folder 18)
    - Egypt, 2003 (Box 131, Folder 19)
    - Egypt, 2006 (Box 131, Folder 20)
  - Card catalog of Mertz's library (series 1) - A-R, undated (Box 132)
  - Card catalog of Mertz's library (series 1) - R-Z, undated (Box 133)
  - Card catalog of Mertz's library (series 2) - A-M, undated (Box 133)
  - Card catalog of Mertz's library (series 2) - M-Z, undated (Box 134)
  - "Political", 1984 (Box 135, Folder 1)
    Includes Mondale/Ferraro buttons
  - Planners, 2009-2012 (Box 135, Folder 2)
  - 80th birthday card (Box 187)
  - 3D plates of Royal Cache TT320 - birthday gift from George B. Johnson, 2012 (Box 187)
  - 70th birthday card (Box 188)
  - 80th birthday gifts (Box 199)
  - Awards
    - Hood College honorary degree, 1991 (Box 183)
    - University of Chicago Alumni Association - Professional Achievement Citation, 2004 (Box 145)
    - Romantic Times - Career Achievement Award for Contemporary Suspense, 1991 (Box 144)
    - Malice Domestic XV - Lifetime Achievement Award, 2004 (Box 181)
    - MWA - Grand Master, 1998 (Box 181)
    - Garden Club of Frederick - Life Member, 1977 (Box 145)
    - Anthony Awards - Grand Master, 1986 (Box 145)
    - American Legion School Award (Box 145)
    - Embassy of the Arab Republic of Egypt - Recognition Award, 2011 (Box 183)
    - Malice Domestic II - Best Novel, 1990 (Box 181)
    - Malice Domestic 24 - Amelia Award, 2012 (Box 181)
    - Mena House Oberoi (Palace at the Pyramids) paperweight (Box 145)
    - Teapot with skull and inscription to Mertz from "Tousignaut-Bodmer Consortium Ltd." (Box 181)
    - GWU Capitol Archaeological Institute - Recognition Award (Box 177)
    - Malice Domestic XV - "Lifetime Acheesement Award", 2003 (Box 193, Folder 17)
    - Agatha Award nomination for Best Non-Fiction - "Amelia Peabody's Egypt", 2003
  - Certificates
    - Malice Domestic - Nominee for Agatha Award for Best Novel of 1994 - Elizabeth Peters (Box 193, Folder 15)
    - Malice Domestic - Nominee for Agatha Award for Best Novel of 1992 - Elizabeth Peters (Box 193, Folder 15)
    - The Literary Cupcake - "awarded to Babs Mertz for excellence in tooth-chipping; snow-storm tolerance; and for being a GLYPH-HEAD!" - presented by Friends of Sedjemef, 9 January 1996 (Box 193, Folder 15)
    - AudioFile's Earphones Award - Serpent on the Crown by Elizabeth Peters, narrated by Barbara Rosenblat, February/March 2006 (Box 193, Folder 15)
    - Malice Domestic - Nominee for the Agatha Award for Best Novel of 1997 - Elizabeth Peters (Box 193, Folder 15)
    - Agatha Award Nomination for Best Novel - The Golden One by Elizabeth Peters, 2002 (Box 193, Folder 15)
    - Agatha Award Nomination for Best Novel - He Shall Thunder in the Sky by Elizabeth Peters, 2000 (Box 193, Folder 15)
    - Hats Off! MWA Grand Master - Barbara Michaels, Elizabeth Peters, 1998 (Box 193, Folder 15)
    - Malice Domestic - Nominee for the Agatha Award for Best Novel of 1998 - Elizabeth Peters (Box 193, Folder 15)
    - Sponsor Member of the Amarna Research Foundation (Box 193, Folder 15)
    - Malice Domestic - Guest of Honor - Elizabeth Peters, 1989 (Box 193, Folder 15)
    - Malice Domestic - Nominee for the Agatha Award for Best Novel of 1989 - Elizabeth Peters (Box 193, Folder 15)
    - Sisters in Crime - Agatha Award Nomination for Outstanding Achievement in Mystery Fiction, Malice Domestic II - Elizabeth Peters, 1990 (Box 193, Folder 15)
    - AudioFile's Earphones Award - Laughter of Dead Kings by Elizabeth Peters, narrated by Barbara Rosenblat, December 2008/January 2009 (Box 193, Folder 15)
    - "Agatha Nominee" badge ribbon (Box 193, Folder 15)
  - Diorama of Mertz's office (Box 146)
  - Beaded black velvet pouch (Box 144)
  - Gold rose brooch in red box (Box 144)
  - Gold cat brooch and mini sarcophagus in Lazarus box (Box 144)
  - Drafting tools (Box 144)
  - Office rolodex, 2013 (Box 144)
  - Calendar collection (Box 184, Box 185)
  - Oak Park Elementary Schools diplomas for Barbara and Kathryn Gross, 12 June 1941 (Box 193, Folder 12)
  - Endorsement from Marion Zimmer Bradley, undated (Box 193, Folder 13)
  - "The Secret Garden" playbill inscribed by Barbara Rosenblatt, undated (Box 193, Folder 14)
  - Memorial poem for an unnamed cat by Margaret Maron, undated (Box 193, Folder 16)
  - Address book, 1966 (Box 193, Folder 18)
  - Skeleton analysis by Aaron Elkins, 1990 (Box 195, Folder 9)
  - Stamp collection - gift of Diane Hewitt (Box 196)
  - Oversize memorials and obituaries, 2013 (Box 197)
- Photographs
  - Photo Albums
    - Four-album set, 1983-1984 (Box 136)
    - Four-album set, 1985 (Box 136)
    - Four-album set, 1988 (Box 136)
    - "I: Roots" (Box 147)
    - "Ia: Oak Park High School" (Box 151)
    - "II: Oak Park" (Box 150)
    - "III: 1950-3" (Box 149)
    - "IV: 1954-59" (Box 148)
    - "7: 1968-72" (Box 158)
    - "8: 1972-6" (Box 171)
    - "9: 1976-8" (Box 172)
    - "10: 1978-9" (Box 178)
    - "12: 1980-1" (Box 169)
    - "13: 1981 and School Pictures" (Box 173)
    - "14: 1982" (Box 152)
    - "15a: Thanksgiving 1983 - Summer 1986 (Box 167)
    - "16: Jennie #1, 1983" (Box 168)
    - "Book Business" (Box 166)
    - "Polaroid #1 - Xmas 1980" (Box 174)
    - "Polaroid #3 - 1982" (Box 179)
    - "Crime Writers International, Stockholm - 1981" (Box 176)
    - "Mother's album - Pictures of the grandkids" (Box 180)
    - 1981-1983? (Box 157)
    - "Egypt 1994 - Elizabeth Peters Tour" (Box 156)
    - "By George [B. Johnson]" (Box 175)
    - "TT320, Royal Cache Tomb - 2004" (Box 153)
    - Mertz in Egypt, 1994? (Box 154)
    - "Family and Pets" (Box 155)
    - August 1986? (Box 159)
    - Barbara and maternal family (Box 164)
    - "Photos of moi in bloomers" (Box 165)
    - England/Scotland Trip (Box 161)
    - House built by Barbara's father in Sedona, Arizona (Box 160)
    - Unknown metal album (Box 163)
    - "My Grandchildren [Barbara's children]" (Box 162)
    - Grace Tragellas's childhood (Box 170)
  - Slides
    - Slide wheel - England, 1957-1968? (Box 137)
      Box incorrectly says "Egypt #1"
    - Slide wheel - Family, 69-76, 1969-1976 (Box 137)
    - Slide wheel - Greece and Istanbul, undated (Box 137)
    - Trip (2 slide boxes), 1957 (Box 137)
    - Arlington (Beth), April 1957 (Box 137)
    - Storybook Park - C. Cod, 1958 (Box 137)
    - "Pete and Beth, Falls Church, Germany, Oak Park", undated (Box 137)
    - "Beth, 3 mos, 9 mos, and Peter", undated (Box 137)
    - "Scenery - Arizona", undated (Box 137)
    - Summer - Beth and Pete (2 slide boxes), 1956 (Box 137)
    - "Charlottesville/Williamsburg/Utah", undated (Box 137)
    - "England, spring 65 - Warwick-Gloucester", 1965 (Box 137)
    - "England, spring 65 - York, Bosworth", 1965 (Box 137)
    - Slide wheel - Jordan/Jerusalem, 1965 (Box 138)
    - Slide wheel - England, 1973? (Box 138)
    - Slide wheel - "Damascus-Beirut", undated (Box 138)
    - "Old Egypt Slides", 1999? (Box 138)
    - Germany, undated (Box 138)
    - England, 1968-1973 (Box 138)
    - England, undated (Box 138)
    - "England, spring 65 / Berkeley-Oxford-Cambridge", 1965 (Box 138)
    - Egypt, undated (Box 138)
    - Egypt slides by Mertz, 1994-1995 (Box 138)
    - "Sun and Post" - portraits of Mertz, undated (Box 138)
  - Printed Photographs
    - Portraits and publicity photos of Mertz, 6 Folders (Box 139, Folder 1-6)
    - Portraits and publicity photos of Mertz (oversize), 1960s-1990s? (Box 188)
    - Panoramic travel photos, 1997-2003?; 3 Folders (Box 139, Folder 7-9)
    - "Malice IV", 1992 (Box 139, Folder 10)
    - "Malice V", 1993; 3 Folders (Box 139, Folder 11-13)
    - "Malice", 1990; 2 Folders (Box 139, Folder 14-15)
    - "England - Sarah, Marian, Bob and Louise B., Paula Gosling and John", 1990 (Box 139, Folder 16)
    - "Oriental Institute - the Drake", 1997 (Box 139, Folder 17)
    - "Grouchercon 9", 1998 (Box 139, Folder 18)
    - "Cambridge and London", undated (Box 139, Folder 19)
    - "Grouchercon - Sandy's", 1997 (Box 139, Folder 20)
    - "Grouchercon - Virgin Gorda", 1996 (Box 139, Folder 21)
    - "Grouchercon", 1992 (Box 139, Folder 22)
    - "Grouchercon - Strasburg, VA", 1995 (Box 139, Folder 23)
    - "Egypt - misc. large for Barbara", 2006-2009 (Box 140, Folder 1)
    - Barbara's 80th birthday, 2009 (Box 140, Folder 2)
    - Beth's wedding, 1978 (Box 140, Folder 3)
    - "Mertz and friends" from Raymond McCoy, 1949 (Box 140, Folder 4)
    - Astoria Public Library - memorial plaque to Mertz's family, 1994? (Box 140, Folder 5)
    - "Pics of Friends from Study", undated (Box 140, Folder 6)
    - Earl D. and Grace E. Gross's tombstone, undated (Box 140, Folder 7)
    - "Elizabeth Peters comes to West 87th Street", undated (Box 140, Folder 8)
    - Portrais of Sandy Ripley, undated (Box 140, Folder 9)
    - "Egypt", 1966 (Box 140, Folder 10)
    - Mertz, friends, and family, 1983-1998?; 6 Folders (Box 140, Folder 11-16)
    - Portraits of Ida Tragellas, undated (Box 189)
    - Portraits of Beth and Peter, 1960s-1970s? (Box 189)
    - "Barbara Mertz - Egypt", September 1961; In Kodalux box, with negatives (Box 196)
    - "Barbara Mertz - Egypt", 1961-1966; In Kodalux box, with negatives (Box 196)
    - Portrait of unknown man (possibly Earl Gross?), undated (Box 197)
    - Barbara Mertz in Peabody attire on canvas, undated (Box 198)
    - Class photo of Bethesda Day School, undated (Box 198)
    - Longfellow Grade School - Eighth Grade Class with signatures on back, June 1941 (Box 198)
  - Negatives
    - "Earliest of Nefret", January 1992 (Box 140, Folder 1)
    - "Xmas 1990 - incl Diesel; Becca 1991 Jan", 1990-1991 (Box 140, Folder 1)
    - "Becca", January 1991 (Box 140, Folder 1)
    - "Becca - Easter", 1992 (Box 140, Folder 1)
    - "Olivia's christening; Easter", 1992 (Box 140, Folder 1)
    - "Chicago and B[oucher]con", October 1992 (Box 140, Folder 1)
    - "Olivia Grace", March 1992 (Box 140, Folder 1)
    - "Olivia and a few cats", July 1992 (Box 140, Folder 1)
    - "Roses #1", June 1992 (Box 140, Folder 1)
    - "Chicago and porch and Jen here", July 1991 (Box 140, Folder 1)
    - "Malice", 1990 (Box 140, Folder 2)
    - "Malice", undated (Box 140, Folder 2)
    - "Malice 2?", 1991? (Box 140, Folder 2)
    - "Ellen", undated (Box 140, Folder 2)
    - "Baltimore Sun", undated (Box 140, Folder 2)
    - "England", 1990 (Box 140, Folder 2)
    - G[roucher]con", undated (Box 140, Folder 2)
    - "Malice IV", 1993? (Box 140, Folder 2)
    - "Garden and B[oucher]con", 1989-1990? (Box 140, Folder 2)
    - "Malice 4", 1994? (Box 140, Folder 3)
    - "Visit to Charlotte", October 1992 (Box 140, Folder 3)
    - "Shepherdess!", undated (Box 140, Folder 3)
    - "Whimsey and Malice Domestic", 1993 (Box 140, Folder 3)
    - "Post Malice Domestic (visit and comm. Party)", 1993 (Box 140, Folder 3)
    - "Whimseys and Malice V", 1995? (Box 140, Folder 3)
    - "Egypt - Giza, Abydos, etc.", undated (Box 140, Folder 3)
    - "Whimseys - Malice Domestic V", April 1993 (Box 140, Folder 3)
    - "Chicago summer", 1990 (Box 140, Folder 4)
    - "Chicago - Becca", 1991 (Box 140, Folder 4)
    - "Negatives", 1991 (Box 140, Folder 4)
    - "Olivia", undated (Box 140, Folder 4)
    - "Spring 90 - garden; June - Chicago", 1990 (Box 140, Folder 4)
    - "Garden", June 1993 (Box 140, Folder 4)
    - "Charlotte", undated (Box 140, Folder 4)
    - "Christmas", 1992 (Box 140, Folder 4)
    - "B[oucher]con", October 1992 (Box 140, Folder 4)
    - "Garden - spring", 1992 (Box 140, Folder 5)
    - "Old black and white negatives of Dad's", undated (Box 140, Folder 5)
    - "Fall, Winter", 1981 (Box 140, Folder 5)
    - "Falls Church - Mother and Dad visit", undated (Box 140, Folder 5)
    - "Kira - o.g. - Xmas cat pie", undated (Box 140, Folder 5)
    - "Egypt", 1991 (Box 140, Folder 5)
    - "Whimsey calendar and publicity", undated (Box 140, Folder 5)
    - "Old negs - Mother and Doug", undated (Box 140, Folder 5)
    - "Sept 1992" (Box 140, Folder 5)
    - Portraits of Mertz by Joan Bingham, undated (Box 140, Folder 5)
    - "Olivia", April 1993 (Box 140, Folder 5)
    - "Chicago", January 1991 (Box 140, Folder 6)
    - "Jan-Feb 1992" (Box 140, Folder 6)
    - "Egypt", 1966 (Box 140, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 140, Folder 6)
    - "Kay and Dick visit", 1970s? (Box 141)
    - "Black and white negatives - Egypt and Rome", undated (Box 141)
    - Box of rolled negatives, undated (Box 141)
- Audio-Visual and Born-Digital
  - Airequipt Ultramatic magazine slide viewer, undated (Box 141)
  - "Graduation", undated; reel (Box 141)
  - "Cats", undated; reel (Box 141)
  - Untitled, undated; reel (Box 141)
  - "Sedona", 1973; reel (Box 141)
  - "In the Parlor - an interview with Barbara Mertz and Charlotte Macleod", 1990; VHS (Box 141)
  - "Mummies I" - A&E, 23 June 1996; VHS (Box 141)
  - "Mummies II" - A&E, 24 June 1996; VHS (Box 141)
  - "The Greatest Pharaohs - I - A&E", 7 July 1997; VHS (Box 141)
  - "Religion - Medina // Egypt Uncovered, Parts 4-5 // Mummies - Roxie", undated; VHS (Box 141)
  - "Egypt Uncovered, Parts 2-3", undated; VHS (Box 141)
  - "Great Egyptians II // The Rebel Pharaoh // Café Productions Ltd", 2 December 1997; VHS (Box 142)
  - "Great Egyptians II // Ramses the Great // Café Productions Ltd", 2 December 1997; VHS (Box 142)
  - "Egypt Uncovered, Parts 1-2", undated; VHS (Box 142)
  - "Secrets of the Pharaohs (DNA and Tut)", 13 February 2001; VHS (Box 142)
  - "Unwrapped - 3 hours of mummies with Bob Brier", 4 December 2000; VHS (Box 142)
  - "Zahi and Maurie - Uncovering Lost Tombs", undated; VHS (Box 142)
  - "The Greatest Pharaohs - II - A&E", 8 July 1997; VHS (Box 142)
  - "The Great Egyptians - Bob Brier, Mystery of Tutankamon", undated; VHS (Box 142)
  - "Great Egyptians II // The Queen Who Would be King // Café Productions Ltd", 2 December 1997; VHS (Box 142)
  - "Signing at Carol & Co.", undated; VHS (Box 142)
  - "Egypt Beyond the Pyramids I", undated; VHS (Box 142)
  - "Egypt Beyond the Pyramids II", undated; VHS (Box 142)
  - "Egypt, Land of the Gods", undated; VHS (Box 142)
  - "King Tut - the Face of Tutankhamun - Wonderful Things", undated; VHS (Box 142)
  - "King Tut - the Face of Tutankhamun - Great Adventure", undated; VHS (Box 142)
  - "Barbara, Sharyn, and Jean - Mystery Bookshop, Bethesda", 10 December 1994; VHS (Box 142)
  - "Greatest Builders of Egypt", undated; VHS (Box 142)
  - "King Tut - the Face of Tutankhamun - the Pharaoh Wakes", undated; VHS (Box 142)
  - "Lost Ships: a Quest", undated; VHS (Box 142)
  - "Abu Simbel, Philae…Saved", undated; VHS (Box 142)
  - INA on ABC's "20/20" (2 tapes), undated; VHS (Box 142)
  - "King Tut - the Face of Tutankhamun - Heads", undated; VHS (Box 142)
  - "Egypt: Quest for Eternity", undated; DVD (Box 142)
  - Filmed by Mertz
    - "Egypt: Saqqara - Geoffrey Martin at the Tomb of Horemheb; Saqqara - First Dynasty mastabas", 1994; VHS-C (Box 142)
    - "Egypt: Cairo Museum; Abusir - Gae and Werner", undated; VHS-C (Box 142)
    - "Luxor - Cairo - Last Days", 1995; VHS-C (Box 142)
    - "Egypt: Egyptian Wedding", 1994; VHS-C (Box 142)
    - "KVS with Dormans, Karnak; Sunset, New Gurnah", undated; VHS-C (Box 142)
    - "Abu Simbel II", undated; VHS-C (Box 142)
    - "Egypt; Olivia - Xmas; Giza", 1993-1994; VHS-C (Box 142)
    - "Aswan to Kasr Ibrim", 1995; VHS-C (Box 142)
    - "Abu Simbel #2", 1995; VHS-C (Box 142)
    - "Amarna #2", 1994; VHS-C (Box 142)
    - "Garden #1", 1995; VHS-C (Box 142)
    - "Garden #3", undated; VHS-C (Box 142)
    - "Egypt - Amarna", 1994; VHS-C (Box 142)
    - "Garden #2", 1995; VHS-C (Box 142)
    - "Garden #3", 1995; VHS-C (Box 142)
    - "Egypt", 1994; VHS (Box 142)
  - "Seeing a Large Cat" - audiobook roughs, undated; audiocassettes (Box 142)
  - "Someone in the House and Borrower of the Night" - audiobook roughs, undated; audiocassettes (Box 143)
  - "Lion in the Valley" - audiobook roughs, undated; audiocassettes (Box 143)
  - "Deeds of the Disturber" - audiobook roughs, undated; audiocassettes (Box 143)
  - "Night Train to Memphis" - audiobook roughs, undated; audiocassettes (Box 143)
  - "The Ape Who Guards the Balance" - audiobook roughs, undated; audiocassettes (Box 143)
  - "The Golden One", undated; audiocassettes (Box 143)
  - "Lord of the Silent", undated; audiocassettes (Box 143)
  - "Falcon at the Portal", undated; audiocassettes (Box 143)
  - "The Ape Who Guards the Balance" - audiobook roughs, undated; audiocassettes (Box 143)
  - "Penny reciting 'fuzzy wuzzy'", undated; audiocassette (Box 143)
  - "American Association of Museums - Mysteries in Museums", undated; audiocassette (Box 143)
  - "The Agony Panel - B[oucher]con", 3 November 2001; audiocassette (Box 143)
  - "Charlotte Macleod in Song", undated; audiocassette (Box 143)
  - "Don't Call Them Gothics - B[oucher]con", 1988; audiocassette (Box 143)
  - "B[oucher]con - Mystery as Social Satire I - MacLeod", 1988; audiocassette (Box 143)
  - "Malice Domestic X - Murder Among Friends", 1998; audiocassette (Box 143)
  - "Panel - Dorothy, Joan, Sarah, A. Simpson, Sharyn", 1997; audiocassette (Box 143)
  - "Interview with Charlotte MacLeod - D'Con", 1988; audiocassette (Box 143)
  - "Barbara Rosenblatz reading excerpts from Agatha nominated short stories - Malice V", 1993; audiocassette (Box 143)
  - "Guardian of the Horizon", undated; CD (Box 143)
  - "Children of the Storm", undated; CD (Box 143)
  - "Children of the Storm - zip design disk", undated; ZIP disk (Box 143)
  - "Other Worlds", undated; 3 1/2 floppy (Box 143)
  - Amelia Peabody's Egypt - production and publicity (AD/KMT), CD (Box 196)
  - The Snake, the Crocodile and the Dog (Die Schlauge das Krokodil und der Hund) - Teil 1, CD (Box 196)
  - The Snake, the Crocodile and the Dog (Die Schlauge das Krokodil und der Hund) - Dateu-CD, text and fotos, CD (Box 196)
  - The Snake, the Crocodile and the Dog (Die Schlauge das Krokodil und der Hund) - Teil 2-B, CD (Box 196)
  - Temples Tombs and Hieroglyphs color, CD (Box 196)
  - Temples Tombs and Hieroglyphs black and white, CD (Box 196)
  - Red Land Black Land color, CD (Box 196)
  - Red Land Black Land black and white, CD (Box 196)
  - Temples Tombs and Hieroglyphs and Red Land Black Land photos, CD (Box 196)
  - Red Land Black Land - all photos/captions, CD (Box 196)
  - Guardian of the Horizon - copy 1, Floppy disk (Box 196)
  - Ape Who Guards the Balance - WordPerfect, Floppy disk (Box 196)
  - Other Worlds - Final for Mac, Floppy disk (Box 196)
  - "George's DVDs of KV63" (2 discs), CD (Box 196)
  - The Amarna Royal Tombs Project, CD (Box 196)
  - Elizabeth Peters at the Field Museum of Natural History - Chicago, CD (Box 196)
  - Barbara Luxor 2007 - W. Raymond Johnson, CD (Box 196)
  - Here and Now - Elizabeth Peters - Egypt Mysteries, 25 November 2003, CD (Box 196)
  - Miscellaneous Egypt photos, CD (Box 196)
  - Christmas 2005/Egypt 2006, CD (Box 196)
  - Temples Tombs and Hieroglyphs - all photos/captions, CD (Box 196)
  - Red Land Black Land - 4c images, CD (Box 196)
  - Additional 4c images for Temples Tombs and Hieroglyphs and Red Land Black Land, CD (Box 196)
  - The Best of Mammoth Crime Fiction (includes "The Locked Tomb Mystery"), CD (Box 196)
  - Barbara Mertz - Egypt Dec. 2002 - if published credit photos to Dennis Forbes, CD (Box 196)
  - The Snake, the Crocodile and the Dog (Die Schlauge das Krokodil und der Hund) - Teil 2-A, CD (Box 196)
  - Dodson for Mertz, CD (Box 196)
  - Additional images for Red Land Black Land and Temples Tombs and Hieroglyphs, CD (Box 196)
  - VHS PlayPak, VHS (Box 196)
  - Red Land Black Land - 4c and black and white halftones, CD (Box 196)
  - Salina, CD (Box 196)
  - Red Land Black Land line drawings, CD (Box 196)
  - Temples Tombs and Hieroglyphs illustrations, 2006, CD (Box 196)
  - Malice XV, CD (Box 196)
- Miscellaneous
  - Christmas card mock-ups, undated (Box 195, Folder 10)
  - Empty folder regarding publishing industry, undated (Box 195, Folder 11)
  - "Blogging the Bible", 2006-2008 (Box 195, Folder 12)
  - Book lists, 2007? (Box 195, Folder 13)
  - Publications, clippings and articles, 1971-1999; 9 Folders (Box 195, Folder 14-22)